

London (Ontario), Canada Github: github.com/olestourko

olestourko@gmail.com Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/olestourko 647-703-7906 Blog: olestourko.github.io

# PROFILE SUMMARY

An experienced and adaptable software developer who likes trying new things.

**GENERAL:** OOP, Design Patterns, Automated Testing, Linux, Docker, Git, Multithreading

LANGUAGES: Python, PHP, Java, Javascript, C#

BACKEND: MVC, Flask, SQLAlchemy, SQL, Laravel, MongoDB, Apache, Nginx

FRONTEND: ¡Query, Knockout.js, HTML, SASS/CSS

## **EXPERIENCE**

**Software Developer** — BriteCore, Springfield Missouri (Remote)

August 2018 — Present

A company that provides a SaaS business platform for insurance companies.

- Implement new user stories and fix defects within a large, mature codebase.
- Work in a 100% distributed team, with all of its unique advantages, risks, and challenges.
- Take defacto ownership of certain features that I tend to work on often.
- Improved development tools by fixing nuisances and improving performance issues.

Tech: Python, Pandas, MySQL, Javascript, Linux, JIRA

**Full Stack Web Developer** — Digital Extremes Ltd, London Ontario A large Canadian game studio best known for the title Warframe.

November 2015 — July 2018

- Key contributor to and maintainer of warframe.com (~0.5M unique daily visitors).
- Automate common tasks and write scripts to sync large datasets.
- Integrate internal and third-party APIs with our web services.
- Work closely with other web developers, departments, and remote team members.

Tech: Laravel, PHP, Python, MySQL, MongoDB, Javascript, SASS, Linux, Perforce, JIRA

Full Stack Web Developer — Northern Commerce Inc, London Ontario A digital agency specializing in ecommerce projects.

April 2014 — October 2015

- Full stack Magento development: implementing custom functionality and integrating extensions.
- Participate in code reviews.

Tech: Magento, PHP, MySQL, Javascript, CSS, Linux

#### SIDE PROJECTS

OpenPay London

February 2018 — Present

An open-source salary information tool for London, Ontario. I want to fix the problem of inadequate market data being available in London.

Website: <u>londontechpay.ca</u> Source Code: <u>github.com/olestourko/open-tech-pay</u>

- Set project goals and successfully launched a working core version.
- Built a completely decoupled frontend and RESTful backend.
- Continuously improving the project based on feedback from the local developer community.

Tech: Python, Flask, Docker, Knockout.js

**SDBudget** 

February 2017 — August 2017

A personal budgeting and cashflow forecasting application. I built a budgeting tool based on my personal spreadsheet system at the time, which works on the concept of a rolling surplus or deficit.

Website: <u>olestourko.github.io/sd-budget</u> Source Code: <u>github.com/olestourko/sd-budget</u>

- Successfully planned and completed the project.
- Used appropriate software design patterns to completely decouple the backend and frontend.
- Wrote an extensive unit testing suite and created concise user documentation.

Tech: Java (SE8), JavaFX, jOOQ, H2DB, JUnit

### **EDUCATION**

**BSc. Computer Science - Ryerson University** 

Graduated 2014

#### PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

**Deep Learning Specialization** - Deeplearning.ai / Coursera A 5-course specialization on neural networks for machine learning.

Completed April 2018

Machine Learning — Stanford University via Coursera
Parallel Programming in Java — Rice University via Coursera
LPIC-1 Linux System Administrator / Comptia Linux+
M101P: MongoDB for Developers

Completed August 2017 Completed October 2017 Completed February 2017 Completed December 2015